嘿 女士 你 女士
[Mimes to Charlene singing] Hey, lady, you, lady
回首你的一生
Cursin' at your life
你是满腹牢骚的母亲
You're a discontented mother
一个普普通通的母亲
And a regimented wife
我不怀疑你的梦想
I've no doubt you dream about
那些你从没做过的事情
The things you never do
但是 我愿有人 告诉我
But I wish someone had've talked to me
我要和你说的
Like I wanna talk to you
呜 我去过佐治亚 去过加利福尼亚
Ooh, I've been to Georgia and California
和任何我能去的地方
And anywhere I could run
和伟人们握手
Took the hand of a preacher man
在阳光下爱抚
And we made love in the sun
但我不再有 友好的表情
But I ran out of places and friendly faces
因为我必须自由
Because I had to be free
我去过伊甸园
I've been to paradise
但我从来不快乐
But I've never been to me
求你 女士 求你 女士
Please, lady Please, lady
不要走开
Don't just walk away
以为我要告诉你
'Cause I have this need to tell you
我今天为什么孤独
Why I'm all alone today
我能看清自己
I can see so much of me
活在你的眼中
Still living in your eyes
你为什么不让我分担这颗疲倦的心
Won't you share a part of a weary heart
活在成千上万的谎言中?
[DOLL SQUEAKS] That has lived a million lies?
我去过希腊
Oh, I've been to Nice and the isle of Greece
游艇中 当我浸在香滨中的时候
While I sipped champagne on a yacht
我在游戏中徘徊
I've moved like Harlow in Monte Carlo
给他们看我的一切
And showed 'em what I've got
我赤身裸体的站在国王旁
I've been undressed by kings
我看到了
And I've seen some things
一个女人所不能看见的
That a woman ain't s'posed to see
我去过极乐世界
I've been to paradise
但我从来就没有
But I've never been
快乐
To me
哦
Ooooh
我去过极乐世界...
I've been to paradise... [APPLAUSE]
从来就没快乐 再来一个!
Never been to me. MAN: More! More!
再来一个!
More! [APPLAUSE AND WOLF WHISTLES]
求你了!
[Man with camp voice] Oh, please!
下一个! 一边去 宝贝!
[Man shouts] Next! Put it away, sweetie!
[CHEERING TURNS TO JEERING]
[CROWD KEEPS JEERING]
啊
Ugh!
[JEERING AND LAUGHTER]
你没事吧 没事
Are you OK? Yeah.
刚才太美了 你们这些混蛋
That was fuckin' charming, you gutless pack of dickheads.
滚开,你条狗 你说什么?
Fuck off, you talentless dog! What was that?
分开双腿 不!
Show us your pink bits! No!
你们知道话筒线 为什么这么长吗?
Know why this microphone has such a long cord?
因为把话筒插在你屁眼里 容易拔出来
So it's easily retrieved after I've shoved it up YOUR arse.
[CROWD HOOTS AND CHEERS]
[DISTANT CONVERSATION AND POUNDING MUSIC]
天那!
Christ almighty!
今天晚上是怎么回事
What the fuck's going on out there tonight?
你疼吗?
Are you hurt?
是那个婊子坐在我的衣服上了
Alright, which one of you bitches sat on my dress?
阿提,你的电话
Tick, darling, it's for you.
你好 是我
Hello. WOMAN: Ding dong, Avon calling.
很久没聊天了
[OMINOUS BOOMING SOUND] Howdy, sunshine. Long time no hear.
哪? 急诊室
Where? Emergency ward A.
贝先生?
[Gasps] Mr Belrose?
什么事?
[BAB Y WAILS FAINTLY] Yes?
你觉得怎么样
WOMAN: So... how about it?
[THUNDERCLAPS ECHO]
[SCREAMING AND SHOUTING]
理我远点 滚!
WOMAN: Leave him alone! MAN: Fuck off!
离开他那
Get... get off him!
出租车!
MAN: Taxi! Taxi!
[PHONE RINGS]
什么事
MAN: Yeah?
班娜丽? 我是阿提
Bernadette? It's Tick.
抱歉这么晚给你打电话 可..
Sorry to call you so late, but I...
你还好吗
Hey, are you OK?
不好
No, I'm not.
怎么回事
Well... what's the matter?
喇叭刚死了
Trumpet just died.
[Priest recites service]
天父是我们的牧人 我们没有所求
The Lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
他叫我们躺下
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
他领我们至静静的小溪边
He leadeth me beside the still waters.
他给了我们灵魂
He restoreth my soul.
领我们走正义的道路
He leadeth me in the paths of righteousness...
他的名字是...
[Sniffles] ...for his name's sake.
我们走进死亡的阴影
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
我们不再有罪恶
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
上帝与我们同在
Thy rod and staff comfort me.
你的权杖赐予我力量
Thou preparest a table before me in the presence of mine enemies.
你用香油沐浴我的头发
Thou anointest my head with oil. My cup runneth over.
你的慈悲将伴我一生
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all my life,
我也必将留住屋宅
and I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
这不公平
It's not fair.
我付出了我的青春
I spent half my life and all my savings
以为找到了好老公
trying to snag a sympathetic husband.
那个自私鬼却一命呜呼了
And the selfish little shit goes and dies on me.
25岁你们在厕所摔了一跤
25 years old, and he goes and slips over in a bathroom.
他没有
He didn't slip.
他在家里漂头发 吸入了过量的气体
He was peroxiding his hair at home and he asphyxiated on the fumes.
我需要一些自由
I need some space.
有人请我去城外表演
I've, um... been asked to do a show out of town.
很好 你为什么不和我一起
That's nice. Well, why don't you come with me?
我需要帮助 我们可以一起用这假期
I'll need some help, and... we could both use the break.
你说得不错. 在哪?
You're not wrong. Where is it?
阿丽泉
Um... Alice Springs.
你在她妈开玩笑吗
You've got to be fucking joking!
女人的 独特面部护肤系列
Wo-Man is a... unique range of speciality facial products
可以更多的表现 我们女人的一面
designed for the more... heavy-duty woman in us all.
这个星期...
Now, um... this week...
对不起
[PHONE RINGS] Excuse me.
你好
TICK: Um... hello?
要多长时间
How long is the run?
四个礼拜
Four weeks.
每晚两场 包住 工资不高
Equity minimum, two shows a night, accommodation included.
[Sighs]
我不能总坐在家里以泪洗面
I can't just sit around here crying all the time.
天那!我的眼泪都要流完了 看起来像皖熊
Jesus! My mascara keeps running. I look like a raccoon.
哈哈 好孩子 这才对
[Laughs] Good girl! That's the spirit.
希望沙漠能 容得下我们两个
Here's hoping the desert's big enough for the two of us.
是三个
Um... three of us.
沙漠假期
[Sings] A desert holiday
来收拾行李
Let's pack the drag away
你吃午饭喝茶 我要带摇头丸
You take the lunch and tea I'll take the ecstasy
滚开! 你这白吃
Fuck off, you silly queer
我要离开这
I'm getting out of here
沙漠假期 好好好
A desert holiday Hip, hip, hip, hip, hooray.
为什么
Why?
为什么不
Why not?
看 他正在向 一个好艺人发展
Look, he's turned into a bloody good little performer.
不错
That's right.
一个好艺人
A bloody good little performer.
每天24小时 每周7天
24 hours a day, seven days a week.
我认为我们远离这些鸟事了
I thought we were escaping this shit.
两一伙 三一群 我的宝贝
Two's company, three's a party, Bernadette my sweet.
我们要收齐假发器 深入不毛
We're unplugging our curling wands and going bush, Felicia.
我们要舍得放弃
Why would you possibly leave all this glamour
把他们抛在脑后
for a hike into nowhere?
你真的想知道吗
You really want to know? Desperately.
真的想 连做梦都想
Well, ever since I was a lad I've had this dream -
我从小就这个梦想 现在终于实现了
a dream that I now, finally, have a chance to fulfil.
就这些吗
And that is...?
去澳大利亚 中部旅行
To travel to the centre of Australia,
假扮女皇
climb Kings Canyon - as a queen -
高跟鞋 还有帽子 要够耀眼
in a full-length Gaultier sequin, heels and a tiara.
太好了 正是这个国家需要的
Great. That's just what this country needs.
一个穿裙子 有老二的
A cock in a frock on a rock.
你们两别吵了
Get back in your kennels, both of you.
现在 我们的第一个问题 要解决的是
Now, the first thing we have to work out...
是我们怎么去
...is how the hell we get there.
嗒嗒
Ta-da!
觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我们什么时候把它还回去
When do we have to return it to the school?
不用还
We don't. We own it.
什么
What?!
我碰到了好人 瑞典的游客
Well, I met some nice 'Svedish' tourists called Lars, Lars and Lars
我一万元的价格买了下来
and I coaxed it out of them for $10,000.
我们服不起的 没错
We can't afford it. Well, that's right.
妈妈 也许你能
[Posh accent] Mummy, maybe a trip to the outback
帮我解决我们的这次旅行
would help me get over this little 'phase' I'm going through.
也许我还会碰上一些 可爱的姑娘
And you never know - I might meet some lovely country girl.
我命名这经济小巴
I hereby christen this budget Barbie camper...
莫兹拉
...Priscilla -
沙漠皇后
Queen of the Desert.
本世纪最慷慨的台词
That must be the understatement of the century.
['GO WEST' B Y THE VILLAGE PEOPLE PLAYS]
一起
SONG: Together
我们一起走
WWe w go ou r way
一起
Together
我们有好的一天
WWe w eave sohme day
一起 妈妈
Together... Mum!
我们手拉手
Your hand in my hand
一起
Together
我们要订计划
We will make the plans...
女士们先生们
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen!
我们今天要 介绍一位勇敢的女士
We're here today to see off a very brave woman
她独自横渡 澳大利亚
who will attempt to cross a continent alone.
她一半的...
On behalf of all her sponsors...
[SHRIEKING AND LAUGHTER]
一起
Together
这是我们要做的
This is what we'll do
向西
Go west
那里很平静
Life is peaceful there
向西
Go west
享受大自然
Lots of open air
向西
Go west
To begin anew
向西
Go west ad es
打开引擎 我们准备出发
...start your engines. This is what we'll do
向西
Go west
冬天的太阳
Sun in wintertime
向西
Go west
我们会很好
We will do just fine
向西
Go west
那里天很蓝
Where the skies are blue
向西
Go west
这是我们要做的
This is what we'll do
一起
Together
我们在那里相爱
We will love the beach
一起
Together
我们互相帮助
We will learn and teach
一起
Together
改良我们的生活
Change our pace of life
一起
Together
我们工作
We will work and strive...
[Both sing]  老家伙 有一套
[Both sing] This old man He played two
玩我的...
He played knick-knack with my poo...
求求你
Please! Knick-knack paddy-whack...
绕了我把 老家伙来到我门前
Give me a break! This old man came rolling home.
胖子矮墙上
Four fat trannies working on the wall
如果有个胖子...
And if one fat trannie should accidentally fall...
我亲爱的
My darling Clementine
嗒嗒嗒
Da da da da...
[Groans]
我们走了多久了
How long have we been on the road?
4个半小时了
4 and a half hours.
我已经头疼了
[Groans] I've got a splitting headache already.
快乐的4小时
Happy hour! Mother's ruin pour moi.
给我一杯
[Sings] Long Island tea... And a Stoli and tonic for me.
听听这个
[Felicia laughs] Stupid cow. Well, listen to this one.
在我们干完了abba
After we did the Abba show,
凯文做了 增大阴颈的手术
Kevin had one of those liposuction penis enlargements.
他做了吗? 做了
He didn't? Yep.
知道他干了什么
Know what they do?
他把脂肪抽出来
They siphon fat from your love handles
然后注射在你的老二上
and inject it into your wing-wang.
啊!
Ugh! Yucky!
那有了新的意思 代替勃起
It gives a new meaning to cracking a fat, though.
吧....
[Both laugh like bleating sheep] Baaa-aaaa! Baaa-aaaa!
看看你们自己 你们俩个笨蛋
Listen to yourselves! You sound like two fat slags at a pie bake-off.
那你在干什么
Well, your contribution to the conversation
不高兴的样子
hasn't exactly made headlines, Bernice.
可怜的凯文的鸡巴
Gee, poor Kevin's dick.
他的内裤都快盛不下了
There can't be much room down there
本来就已经没什么地方了
with his brain taking up so much space already.
[Copies bleating laughter]
我也加入
No, I'll join this conversation
来大讲人家的闲话
on the proviso that we stop bitching about people,
讲人家的 阴颈大小
talking about wigs, dresses, bust sizes,
和一些乱七八糟的 鸟事
penises, drugs, nightclubs and bloody Abba!
有什么可说的 是吧
Doesn't give us much to talk about then, does it?
帮我正是一下
Hey, can you confirm a rumour for me?
她的真名字是茹夫吗? 对吗?
Is it true her real name's Ralph? Shh!
你们喜欢怎么样 小男孩小姑娘们
How do you like your little boys, girls?
你们不用回答
You don't have to answer that.
天那 荒山野岭的
Oh, my God. What is this - 'Outback with Benny Hill'?
把早饭明天早上8点钟 放在门外就行了
Just leave mine outside the door at about 8am
我要土司 还要桔汁
along with an orange juice and toast, please.
当然 太太
[American accent] Why, certainly, madam.
你还要点果酱吗?
Would you like vegemite or jam with that?
开门
Er... knock knock. Room service.
你会看字吗 请勿打扰
Can't you read the sign - Do not disturb?
明天早上在来 哈哈 开门
Come back in the morning. Ha ha. Open the door.
晚安 晚安
Goodnight, Bernice. Goodnight, Mitzi.
快他妈开门
Open the fucking door!
[EXAGGERATED SNORING]
[SNICKERING]
你们要是不开门 我就要唱歌
OK, if you don't open the door... I'm gonna sing.
好 你们逼我的
Fine. You asked for it.
我不在乎 如果太阳不再发光
[Sings] I don't care if the sun don't shine
我就在晚上快乐
I get my loving in the evening time
我和爱人在一起的时候
When I'm with my baby
和太阳没关系
It's no fun with the sun around
因为我们是在晚上出发
'Cause I get going when the sun goes down
和我爱人
And I meet my baby...
[Bangs on bus]
我们亲呀亲
That's when we kiss and kiss and kiss
再亲呀亲
And then we kiss some more
别问我多少次 晚安
Don't ask how many times... Night, John-boy.
哇
[Screams] Waaah!
我真的就快睡着了
I'm seriously falling asleep.
该你了就撑着点吧
It's your shift and you're sticking to it.
你这个小贱人
Serves you right for staying out all night... slut.
我抗不住
Well, I won't make it.
我不在乎 如果太阳不发光
[Sings] I don't care if the sun don't...
哦 滚开
Oh, fuck off, grandma.
你还好吗
You alright?
我 我好极了
Me? Yeah. I'm fine.
想事呢
I'm just thinking.
别当英雄
SONG ON CASSETTE: Billy. Don 't be a hero
不要自甘堕落
Don 't be a fool with your life
不要~
rBiWWy, don, t bdo a hdoro
回来呀~
Come back and make me your wife...
[TYRES SCREECH]
我们开始出发
And as Billy started to go
底下你漂亮的头发
She said. Keep your pretty head low
不要当英雄
Billy. Don 't be a hero ... [BRAKES SQUEAL]
回来呀
Cdomdo bacmk tdo mdo,,
对不起
Sorry.
妈的
Shit!
怎么了
What is it?
也许我们应该坐飞机
Perhaps we should've flown.
[THUNDEROUS MUSIC]
错了 谢谢参与
Bzzt! Wrong! But thanks for playing.
还有谁 不了
Anyone else? No!
该你了
Witchetty grub. Your turn.
看看我的小眼睛 以R开头的东西
I spy with my little eye something beginning with 'R'.
- 直肠? - 不
- Rectum. - No.
- 海盗帮? - 不
- Ring pirate. - No.
道路
Road.
好吧 你是怎么了
Alright, that's it. What's the matter with you?
没什么事 亲爱的 没叫我亲爱的
Nothing, darling. Don't 'darling' me, darling.
看看你自己 像只猫
Look at you. You've got a face like a cat's arse.
没什么 我只是为演出担心
Now 'fess up. Just... worried about the show.
我们还什么都 没做呢
We haven't done any rehearsals yet...
我们有2个星期呢 足够排练的时间
We've got two weeks! There's plenty of time to rehearse.
现在你的问题是什么
Now, what is your problem?
没问题 我只是...
No problem. I just...
我就是想演出漂亮点
I just want this show to be good.
你是怎么 得到的这个工作
How the fuck did you get this job, Mitzi?
是谁会在那种不毛之地 开酒吧
Who is the fish that runs this hotel in the middle of nowhere, anyway?
你妈妈 不 我老婆
Your mother? No, my wife.
噢别告诉我 你有前男友
Ooh, don't tell me you've got an ex-boyfriend
你还挺风流的
tucked away out here somewhere.
不 他是我老婆
No, my WIFE!
我结婚了
I'm married.
[BRAKES SCREECH]
哦 妈的
[GLASS SHATTERS] Oh, fuck!
[MAJESTIC ORGAN MUSIC]
几年后我的账户 的钱用完了
And when the joint bank account ran dry after a couple of years...
..我想我喜欢她的结婚戒指 多过喜欢我的
...I guess I preferred her wedding ring to mine, so... no drama.
我们交换了戒指 各走各的
We swapped and called it a day.
太不正常了
This is getting too weird.
你和一个女人
YOU and a woman.
她是干什么的
What did she do for kicks?
她把桶套在你头上
Put a bucket on your head and swing off the handle?
有两件事我不喜欢你
There are two things I don't like about you, Felicia.
你的脸! 还有你得嘴
Your face! So how about shutting both of them?
怪不得你没人要
Well, at least this explains your abysmal batting average, Mitz.
我一直奇怪你怎么这么怪
I often wondered why your dance card was so empty.
原来你一直没离婚
You never got a divorce, then?
女孩们 我能说什么呢
Well, girls, what can I say?
这是个秘密
Here's to a secret very well kept.
不应该这么说 对吗
Shame it won't stay that way, isn't it?
我有一些小惊喜 你们想听听吗
Mmm! Got any more little surprises you'd like to share with us?
有小孩吗 藏在什么地方
Haven't got any kids stashed away out there, have you?
看
Look...
我从来没说慌
...I haven't lied about anything.
6年后我接到她的电话 还救命
After six years I get phone call out of nowhere, screaming for help,
天知道 我欠她这次
and Christ knows I owe her some favours.
对不起这些我一直没和你们说
I'm sorry that I never told you.
但我不后悔带你们来这
[Tearfully] I'm not sorry that you're here.
别担心
Don't worry about it, dolls.
其实我嫉妒死了
I'm as jealous as all hell.
为什么
What?
那是个大婚礼吗
So, was it a big wedding?
很多礼物吗
Get lots of pressies, did you?
我希望我当时够年龄 参加就好了
I wish I was OLD enough to have been there.
哈哈
Oh, ha ha.
我会送你..
I would've bought you
一套性感浴衣
a lovely matching set of hers and hers bathmats.
哦你歇会把 那不是你的生活
Oh, give it a rest. Not on your life!
设想一下 伟大的阿提 和他羞答答的新娘
Oh, imagine! Mitzi the magnificent and her blushing bride.
走路时一定让你的 高跟受了不少苦
Mowing those lawns must've been murder on your heels, though.
好了 你说够了
Alright, Felicia. That's enough.
我们玩点钱的 也许能让你闭嘴
Let's put some money in that seething cesspool mouth of yours.
要是我赢了
If I win this game,
你永远不能在 提我老婆
you will NEVER mention my wife EVER in my presence again, OK?
如果你赢了 要什么都行
And if I win? Name your price.
好
Well, now...
我会要什么呢
What would I like
世界上最重要的
more than anything else in the whole wide world?
快
Snap!
快点
Better be quick.
现实点
SONG: About being true
我们要克服困难
And all of the trouble we've been through
不要向后看
Oh, please don't talk about all the plans we had
我们来解决它
For fixing this broken romance
我要跳舞
I want to go where the people dance...
我在她妈干什么
What the fuck am I doing?
你快给我 滚开 你这苯猪
Take that bloody frock off, Felicia - don't make it worse than it is.
你没机会了
Think I'll let YOU get all the attention? No chance!
我们走 去逛街
Come on, girls. Let's go shopping.
我的天那
Oh, for Christ's sake!
我喜欢夜生活
I love the night-life I've got to boogie
跳舞呀 哈哈
On the disco Ah-ha, oh, yeah
我喜欢夜生活
Oh, I love the night-life
我要跳舞
I've got to boogie
啊
On the disco Ah-ha, oh, yeah...
这有跳舞
Oh, I just adore these hats!
请不要谈感情
Please don't talk about love tonight
我不想听
Your sweet talking won't make it right
爱情都是谎言
Loving lies just bring me down
当你有了女人
When you've got women all over town
你可以给出全部的爱
You can love them all
当你...
And when you're through
她们也许会..
Maybe they'll make...
不是在开玩笑吧
[MUSIC FADES] You've got to be kidding!
欢迎来马里奥宫
[Thick Italian accent] Welcome to Mario Palace!
请进
Come in. Come in.
Come in.
我能为你做什么呢
What can I do for you?
我们要间屋子
You'd like a room, madam?
好极了
Subtle.
妙极了
Oh, tackarama!
这些都是谁画的
Who does all the painting around here?
一个没有手臂的人 太难看了
Someone with no arms or right foot, by the look of things.
别碰那个十字架
Ugh, for goodness sakes get down off that crucifix!
有人需要那木头
Someone needs the wood.
这里有什么
What have we here?!
太棒了
What fun! Baby bottles of booze!
哦
Oh!
孩子们 让我教教你们
Gather round, girls - let me show you a trick.
喝下这个
You, um, drink the gin...
阿
Ah!
然后用水把 他装满
...ah, fill the bottle with water and... put it back.
那威士忌怎么办
Va-t'en vous. What about the Scotch?
找点免费茶 不就完了
Ah... that's where the complimentary tea bags come in handy.
太聪明了 孩子们
Very clever. Cheers, girls.
祝贺你  阿提 你做到了
And congratulations, Mitzi darling. You did it.
扮成女人去逛街
One lap of the Broken Hill main drag IN drag.
还要教你
That'll teach you to take on
怎么和男生打交道
the Fairmont Boys School snap champion.
为离开那个鬼巴士干杯
Here's to being off the fucking bus.
干
[Sighs] Chookers.
干 干
Chookers. Chookers.
没有地方去玩
So... all dolled up and nowhere to go.
我死也不会留在这里的
I sure as shit am not going to sit in here all evening.
我也去
I'm in!
好
Oh, alright.
希望有间像样的酒吧
Here's hoping they have a decent cocktail bar.
[LOUD CONVERSATION AND HONKY-TONK PIANO]
[SILENCE]
你好
Hello.
我要一杯伏特加
Could I please have a Stoli and tonic,
一杯柠檬大吉利
a bloody Mary and a lime daiquiri, please?
好
WOMAN: Well!
这猫惹来什么东西
Look what the cat dragged in!
是什么贵客
What have we got here, eh?
两个脱衣舞女
A couple of showgirls, have we?
你们是哪的
Where did you ladies come in from?
乡下的
Uranus?
我能要杯... 不能
Could I please have a Stol... No!
不给你
Ya can't have!
你什么也得不到
Ya can't have nothin'.
我们这里对于你们这些人 什么也没有
We've got nothin' here for people like you. Nothin'!
听着
Now listen here, you mullet.
你不如找点 好点的卫生巾
Why don't you just light your tampon and blow your box apart?
才不会把这弄脏
Because it's the only bang you'll ever get, sweetheart!
[Laughs uproariously]
[Bystanders laugh heartily]
[PIANO STARTS PLAYING AGAIN LAUGHTER CONTINUES]
我要在晚上快乐
[Felicia sings] I get my loving in the evening time
当我和我的宝贝儿..
When I'm with my baby
噢 没意思
Oh, it's no fun...
有什么比这更好的
[Slurs drunkenly] What could be more soothing
辛苦了一整天
than coming home after a hard day's work down the mine
女人是我们的一切
to the wo-man in us all?
不要再给钱了 好吗
Now, don't send any money. OK?
[Felicia continues singing drunkenly]
噢!!
ONLOOKERS: Ooh!
[MUSIC BUILDS SUSPENSEFULLY]
哦!
ONLOOKERS: Ooh!
Oooooh!
哦
OOOOH!
妈的
Shit!
我能看见的只有女人
All I can see is female impersonators.
[HONKY-TONK PIANO JANGLES DISCORDANTLY]
[Bystanders laugh and cheer]
今天是第一回
This has got to be a first.
阿雪多年来没有对手
Nobody's ever outdrunk old Shirl before.
你是在那学得喝酒
Where'd you learn to throw 'em back like that?
这才是我们的好女孩
That's our girl, Bernadette.
200年来她一直跟 姐妹歌舞团
Stumbling around the pub circuit with Les Girls for 200 years
一定学到了什么
must've taught her something.
你真是太厉害了
[Laughs] You're a bloody marvel, Bernie.
摆脱 班尼 那是什么
Bernadette, please. What's that?
我不叫班尼 他说他不叫班尼
My name isn't Bernie. She said her name isn't Bernie.
是罗夫
It's Ralph!
[Laughs drunkenly]
来呀
[Groans] Come on! Oh!
噢!
Oh! Oh! [Laughs]
你叫我什么? 你叫我什么?
What did you call me? What did you call me what?
你在酒吧叫我什么?
What did you call me back there in the bar?
罗夫
Sorry... Ralph! [Sniggers]
你他妈傻呀!
You fucking idiot! Oh!
操!
[Groans] Oh! Fuck!
那妈的
[Snores ] Oh! Fuckin'... Oh! Fuck! [Snores]
滚开 你他妈的
Get off me, you fuckin'... Oh!
被担心 是我的脑袋
Don't worry. It's only my fucken head!
你的脑袋还没有老二儿大
At least the bump on your head's bigger than your prick!
你这头蠢猪
Why don't you ust get fucked, you stupid old fist?!
滚开
Oh, piss off, you little faggot!
你他妈无聊了
Listen, you're so bloody boring...
你得嘴相鸡巴一样大
If your mouth was as big as your dick...
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[MUSIC SWELLS DRAMATICALLY]
早晨好 好
Good morning. Morning.
太有趣了
TONY: It's funny, you know.
在难我也能得到
No matter how tough I think I'm getting...
..依然很疼
...it still hurts.
希望他还能工作
Hope it still works.
这没什么销路
Don't have much call for it here.
你们是哪来的
Where are you blokes from?
村里的 好极了
Uranus. Oh, good. [Chuckles]
[SASS Y JAZZ MUSIC]
我要游泳
SONG: Fish gotta swim Birds gotta fly
我要爱一个人知道她死去
I got to love one man till I die...
那 左转!
There! Left!
希望你知道你在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
要再走两天路程
If we stick to the sealed road we'll be going another two days.
告诉我他很懒 告诉我他很慢
Tell me he's lazy Tell me he's slow...
走捷径
Take the short cut.
告诉我我疯了 可能
Tell me I'm crazy Maybe I know
不能停止爱那个人
Can't help lovin' that man of mine.
[Mimes to woman singing 'Sempre Libera' from Verdi's 'La Traviata']
[OPERA KEEPS PLAYING]
我要打烂他的脸
One more push, I'll smack his face so hard
我要让他用呀刷刷完屁股 在刷牙
he'll have to stick his toothbrush up his arse to clean his teeth.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
别再惹他了
[Chortles] Just lay off!
我说了不要再用 那个R开头的字了
I said not to use the 'R' word. What did you go and do?
我说了不要再用 那个R开头的字了?
我只是开个玩笑
I was only having fun. Fun?
你该吗用门掩我的手指
What else do you do for amusement - slam your fingers in car doors?
什么意思
What's the point?
你喜欢发火
It gives me a kick seeing people get hot-headed.
你出生的时候 医生侮辱你妈妈吗?
Is it true when you were born the doctor slapped your mother?
还是因为你的 同年很不幸
What sort of... bent childhood did you have, Adam Whitely?
亚当
[BATH WATER SPLASHES] MAN: Adam! Adam!
过来这
Come in here, boy.
来坐下
Come and sit over here.
你想和周叔叔玩吗?
Would you like to have some fun with Uncle Barry?
我们要玩一个特别的游戏,
We're gonna play a SPECIAL game,
但你不能和别人说
but you can't tell anybody
永远 好吗
ever, ever, ever, OK?
现在我要你把你的手拿下来
Now, I want you to put your hand down here
轻轻的  好吗?
and pull very gently, OK?
轻轻的
Very gently.
好极了
That's good. That's good.
哦!
[SUCTION NOISE] [Groans] Ooh!
天那 快帮忙
[Grunts] Jesus Christ, Adam! Get help!
亚当 周叔叔的鸡鸡贝卡住了
Adam, Uncle Barry's penie-pie is caught in the drain.
去叫妈妈
Get Mummy. Get Mummy!
不 不是什么意思
[Shouts] No! Whaddya mean 'no'?!
永远不告诉别人
[Guffaws] Never, ever, ever! [Laughs]
最妙的部分就是
You know the best part? [Keeps laughing]
妈妈出去玩高尔夫了
Mum was out playing golf
那个老流氓在那 卡了7个小时!
and the dirty old fuck was stuck there for seven hours!
我认为它被拉的又细又长了
I thought they were small and wrinkled
在他们进水之前!
BEFORE they got in the water!
[Both keep laughing]
嘿 我有一个笑话
Hey, I've got a joke.
谁想听
Who wants to hear a joke?
讲把
Come on, Bernice,
你会笑得连 眉毛都变了颜色的
you'll laugh SO hard, your lashes will curl by themselves.
那就讲你的下流笑话
Do tell us your hilarious joke.
好
OK.
很久很久以前
Well, once upon a time, many moons ago,
有个很出名的印第安人 叫法阿维.
there was a famous bunch of Indians called the Fuck-are-we tribe.
一天他的儿子问他
One day, the son of the great Indian chief says to his father,
爸爸为什么我的小朋友叫小鹰'
Dad, why is my friend Little Hawk called Little Hawk?
他爸爸说
And his father says...
你为什么要这样问 土到发?
Why do you ask... Two Dogs Fucking?
还没完
That's NOT the end of the joke.
我继续
So anyway, back to me.
[LOUD CLUNKING AND HISSING]
天那 怎么了?
Jesus! What's happening?
不知道
[LOUD BANG] Um... I don't know.
[CLUNKING RATTLING AND HISSING CONTINUES]
[LOUD BANG]
[ENGINE STOPS ABRUPTLY AIR HISSES]
我的天那
Oh, my God.
[WIND WHISTLES]
哦
Oh, Felicia.
我们他妈在那
Where the fuck are we?
[OMINOUS DRUMBEAT AND MUSIC]
靠 我靠
[Voice echoes] Shit! Shit! Shit!
[DESOLATE WIND BLOWS]
妈的
Oh, shit!
我转转看看
Well, I've had a look around
我对机械一无所知
and we can safely assume that I now know less about motors
比刚才揭开机器盖子还迷茫
than I did when I lifted up that, uh... that bonnety thing.
现在怎么办
Now what?
先不去想他 先来吃早餐
Let's not think about it yet and eat brekkie, shall we?
哦 好主意
Oh, that's a novel idea.
我们盛死自己
Let's stuff ourselves to death.
想想会是什么样的头条
Imagine the headlines.
鲸鱼在沙漠自杀
'Whales beach themselves in the outback'.
女人离奇暴死
'Mystery bumsticks dead in drag'.
我们没可能走回去
There's no point walking back.
我看到的唯一生物是 蜥蜴
The only life I've seen is hypnotised bunnies
大部分已经被过往 的车辆压扁了
and they're now mostly wedged in the tyres.
真的会有路过的这两的
Surely somebody will drive past. We'll keep the fire burning.
对我们为救兵干杯
Yes, and toast marshmallows and chill champagne for their arrival.
要是他们不经过呢
What if they DON'T drive past?
看你在这帮倒忙 吃你的饭吧
Look, you're not helping here. Just eat your hormones.
为什么我们不走大路
Help. Why didn't we stick to the main road?
有什么不一样 你引起的这些
What difference does it make?! You started this, Anthony Belrose.
想想 我们怎么能回去
Start thinking about how to get us back
不然你竟没机会再 做老公
or I don't fancy your chances of being a husband again.
天那 我们要怎么样
Jesus. What are we gonna do?
我们要 先补补装
We're gonna start with a little face-lift.
换挑新裙子 让自己开开心
Nothing like a new frock to brighten up your day.
紫色
Purple?!
不是紫色 是藕荷色
It's not PURPLE. It's lavender.
怎么样
Whaddya think?
哦不错 是个好主意
Oh, it's nice... in a hideous sort of a way.
你们去哪
Where are you going?
你认为我还在这等死吗
If you think I'm sitting around
看这个毕加索作画
watching Picasso take on the public transport system
还有别的事要做
you've got another thing coming.
我几个小时后 会带救兵来
I'll be back with the cavalry in a few hours.
变性人向南走 从此消失
There goes a transsexual. Last seen heading south.
我们叫她班尼 其实她叫...
We called her Bernie, but her real name was...
亚当
Adam!
[DESOLATE MUSIC AND CHANTING]
[TINKLING SOUND]
[MUSIC SWELLS DRAMATICALLY]
喂
[Shouts] Cooee! [VOICE ECHOES]
Cooee! [ECHO REVERBERATES]
我会幸免...
[Sings 'I Will Survive' softly]
[Keeps singing softly]
[MYSTICAL TINKLING SOUND SNAKE-LIKE RATTLE]
[MUSIC AND SLOW CHANTING CONTINUES]
[DESOLATE WIND BLOWS]
[FLIES BUZZ]
[DESOLATE MUSIC]
[MUSIC BUILDS OMINOUSLY]
啊
[Yells] Aaaggh!
[WIND WHISTLES]
[Continues singing 'I Will Survive']
[MYSTICAL TINKLING SOUND]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[Pants]
[FLIES BUZZ]
哦
[Moans] Oh!
救命
[Calls weakly] Help! Help!
那是什么 哪?
What's that, Pa? What?
在那
Up there, yer nong.
看那个女人
Looks like a woman!
救命
Help!
哦 谢天谢地
[Sighs] Oh, thank God.
[Sighs with relief]
[FLIES BUZZ]
谢谢你
Thank you.
你说不出来我有多高兴
I can't tell you how grateful I am.
我走着来找你们
[Sings] I just walked in to find you here
看你愁眉不展
With that sad look upon your face...
[CAR APPROACHES]
[FLIES BUZZ CAR DRAWS NEARER]
你他妈太棒了
You fucken beauty!
哦 他妈的
Ooh, ooh, shit. Ooh.
班尼 我很高兴见到你
Aaah! Bernie, I'm so glad to see you!
我希望我也是
I wish I could say the same. [AII laugh]
来见见我们的救命恩人
I was just drawing up the will. Come and meet our saviours.
托尼 亚当 这是使先生和太太
Tony, Adam, this is Mr and Mrs Spencer.
你好 你好
Hello! Hello!
停!
Stop! Stop!
妈的
Shit. [Sighs]
天那 看看你自己 阿提
Oh, for goodness sakes, look at yourself, Mitz.
你要我和你说多少遍 你穿女颜色不好看
How many times do I have to tell you green isn't your colour?
[CackIes ] [Cackles]
你想喇叭吗
Do you think about Trumpet much?
不
No.
喇叭这是个喜欢变性 的好孩子
Trumpet was just a nice kid who had a thing about transsexuals.
很多人都一样
Lots of people do.
那类的..
Sort of... bent status symbol, you know.
我的女朋友以前是男的
My girlfriend used to be a boyfriend - that sort of thing.
很受欢迎
Always good for a supper invite.
比没有强
Still... it was better than nothing.
没什么像男人
Nothing. Nothing for miles.
[INTRODUCTION TO ABBA'S 'FERNANDO' PLAYS]
你能听见鼓声吗?
[Sings along] Can you hear the drums, Fernando...
我以前说过 我现在再说一遍
I've said it before and I'll say it again.
再也没什么abba了.
No more fuckin' Abba.
既然有时间 就应该好好利用
OK, we may as well put the time to good use.
来吧 姑娘们
Come on, girls. Off your snatches.
排练
Rehearsal time.
不不不
[Hums] Nah, nah, nah...
你回过神来了
And so you're back From outer space...
好了准备好了吗?
OK? Two bobs to start with, alright?
没意思 真的?
Boring. Ready?
嗒嗒嗒
[Keeps humming tune] Da da da da
嘀嘀嘀嘀
Dee dee dee dee
嘀嘀嘀
Dee dee dee dee dee dee
向上看
This look upon your face...
我几年前也干过
Oh, I did this years ago.
那是做得很美 你做得很好
You did it SO beautifully and darling, you do it SO well.
真的
Right, from the top.
一 二
One, two...
来 开始
Go on, now go
走出门
Walk out the door
转个圈
Just turn around now
因为你已不再受欢迎了
'Cause you're not welcome anymore
不要再用再见吓我
Weren't you the one who tried to hurt me with goodbye...
啊！
[AII shriek] Aaaagh!
你好
Hello.
夜色不错
Nice night for it.
[GUITAR MUSIC QUIET LAUGHTER AND CONVERSATION]
还不错
[Man sings blues song] Well, I feel alright
感觉不错
Feel alright
对 不错
Yes, I feel alright
我感觉不错
Well, I feel alright with you right by my side...
[GUITAR MUSIC CONTINUES DOG BARKS]
[Stops playing]
[LAUGHTER AND CONVERSATION STOP ABRUPTLY]
我想我们打断了你们的派对
I think we just... crashed a party.
没关系的 别这么说
[Laughs] No, come on. You'll be right.
[GUITAR PLAYING LAUGHTER AND CONVERSATION CONTINUE]
[SINGING AND LAUGHTER]
[DOG YELPS]
欢迎 请坐
Welcome to my office. Have a seat.
去土著派对要这样吗?
Bernice, what possibly possessed you to wear THAT to a corroboree?
闭嘴
Shut your face.
[ANIMATED TALKING AND LAUGHTER]
[HYSTERICAL LAUGHTER AND TALKING]
好 太妙了
Bravo! Fabulous!
[They keep clapping]
好女孩们该我们上场了
Well, girls, I guess it's our turn.
['I WILL SURVIVE' INTRO PLAYS]
开始我很怕
SONG: At first I was afraid I was petrified
一直认为我 活不了
Kept thinking I could never live without you by my side
可后来我意识到 我犯了多大的错
But then I spent so many nights thinking how you did me wrong
我长大了
And I grew strong
学会了面对孤独
And I learned how to get along
你从另一个世界 回来
And so you're back From outer space
我走进你 用我悲伤的眼神
I just walked in to find you here with that sad look upon your face
我应该对准我的 钟表
I should have changed that stupid lock
让你留下你的钥匙
And made you leave your key
如果我知道 你将会回来
If I'd known for just one second you'd be back to bother me
现在就离开
Go on now go
走出那门
Walk out the door
转身
Just turn around now
因为你不再受欢迎
'Cause you're not welcome anymore
你以不是再用再见伤害我的人
Weren't you the one who tried to hurt me with goodbye
你认为我会死掉
Did you think I'd crumble Think I'd lay down and die?
哦 我不会
Oh, no, not I
我会幸免
I will survive
就像我知道怎么爱
As long as I know how to love I know I'll stay alive
我会付出我的一切
I've got all my life to live and I've got all my love to give
我会幸免 我会幸免
And I'll survive I will survive
嘿
Hey, hey...
[MUSIC CONTINUES] [Man plays didgeridoo]
看看那个
Hey, take a look at that.
哦 我有个主意
Ooooh! I've got an idea!
我没有摔倒
It took all the strength I had not to fall apart
我要捡起我 破碎的心
Just trying hard to mend the pieces of my broken heart
我付出很多的夜晚 来感觉我自己的存在
And I spent, oh, so many nights just feeling sorry for myself
我哭过 但我现在要抬起头
I used to cry But now I hold my head up high
你看我
And you see me
就像崭新的人
[People chant with music] Somebody new
我不会再爱上你
I'm not that chained-up little person still in love with you
你不会感到自由
So you felt like dropping in and just expect me to be free
现在我要为我 爱的人付出我的爱
Now I'm saving all my lovin' for someone who's lovin' me
离开我
Go on now go [Chanting and didgeridoo continue]
从门出去
Walk out the door
转身走吧...
Just turn around now 'cause you're not welcome anymore...
[MUSIC AND LAUGHTER FADE]
你穿成女人的样子 争钱吗
So... you actually make money by dressing up like a woman?
对 我能靠一双 高跟鞋走天下
Oh, sure. You can make a fine living in a pair of heels.
你要入行吗
Why, Allen? Do you want a job? [Chuckles]
[WIND WHISTLES]
只有这件衣服了吗
Oh! If only this dress could talk.
有时我想知道 我的品味怎么来的
Sometimes I wonder where I get my taste.
肯定不是我妈妈的
Definitely not my mother.
太糟糕了让他帮我 挑衣服
Serves me right for letting her buy me these awful clothes.
这是什么
What's this?
之可是我的宝贝 世界上最好的
That, darling, is my most treasured possession in the whole wide world.
什么东西
But what is it?
上次我去abba
Once I went on a pilgrimage backstage to an Abba concert,
想不到那个公主接见了我
hoping to grab an audience with Her Royal Highness, Agnetha.
在她去厕所的时候
Well, when she ducked into the ladies loo,
我跟她一起去的
naturally I followed her in...
在她完事以后
...and after she'd finished her business
我去了她的坑
I ducked into the cubicle
她留给了我这个礼物
only to find she'd left a little gift in the toilet bowl.
你在和我说什么
What are you telling me?
这是abba的大便
This is an Abba turd?
我知道我们能用他干什么
I know what we can do with THIS.
你好了吗
Are you right?
等等
Hang on!
好了 开始
OK! Go!
呜!!
[MAJESTIC OPERATIC MUSIC] Whoo-hoo!
好呀!
There! Whoo-hoo!
[Laughs]
[MAJESTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
午安 是什么毛病
Afternoon. What seems to be the problem?
[Dog barks]
好狗
What a nice dog.
他叫什么
What's its name?
赫比
Herpes.
她还好吗
If she's good, she'll heel.
事情看起来很清楚
Things get pretty quiet around here.
我们想来点娱乐
We're a bit starved of entertainment.
好极了
Glad we could oblige.
那个怎么样
How does it look?
你们的油堵住了 全都是尘土
Well, your gas tank's chock-a-block full of crud.
路太不平了
Travelling a rough road on a low tank chucks it into the motor.
所以尘土进入了油嘴 把它堵住了
Your fuel line's blocked, injectors are stuffed...
能修吗?
So does that mean you can fix it? In the short term.
你们需要一个新的
What you blokes need is a new gas tank.
你们这没有吧
Don't suppose there's one lying around?
没有 对不起
[Chuckles] No, sorry.
可以弄来一个 但要几周的时间
Could pick one up in Coober Pedy in about a week.
你们想什么时候到达目的地 6天后
When do you have to be in Alice? Six days.
我们就修吧 听天由命了
We can clear it out and hope for the best.
你能做到的
You might make it.
你要不试试就不知道
Won't know unless you try.
喝东西
[Woman squeals] Refreshments!
好
Lemonade here - I make!
这太好了
That's very nice, darling. Please... go back inside.
我自己做的
Lemonade here - I make. Lemonade for guests.
不了亲爱的
No, darling, please! [Snarls viciously]
我还做了曲奇
I make chockrit cracker!
谢谢
Thank you!
我要放奶油
We put cream on?
不 那是擦脸的
Er... no, no. It's... um... face cream.
擦脸的 哦
It's for face. Ah!
谢谢你们
Bob, Cynthia - thank you.
我喜欢你们的食物
I love lamb with meringue.
谢谢你们的款待
Thank you for the company.
像我说的 我们至立很少有客人
Like I said, new faces are hard to come by here.
你们要去干什么
What were you doing off the highway?
好 这可是一个好问题
Oh, now, that's a bloody good question.
这里很少见 你们这样的人
Glad you bothered. Don't get your type out here very often.
我也喜欢唱歌
Me like to sing too - me like... Yeah, pretty damn quiet.
我要开一个...
Thought about opening a video business,
但是我要先有一个电视机
but I suppose we gotta wait for television first.
我给你们表演
Me perform for you. Me dance too.
我老婆以前 也是从事表演的
My wife was in the, uh... entertainment business.
你要表演吗
Yeah. You perform here?
在这里
You thinking of performing here?
反正你们要在这里过一夜
I mean, you'll be here at least another night.
我还没想过呢
Um... well, the thought hadn't really... crossed my mind.
我们可以去酒吧 人人都喜欢的
Well, I'll talk to Wally at the pub. Everybody would love it.
我们不认为我们的 表演适宜
Oh, I'm not sure our show would go down too well out here.
你们演的是什么
What kind of cabaret do you do?
我们穿女人的衣服
We dress up in women's clothes
走来走去的 扮口型唱歌
and parade around mouthing the words to other people's songs.
你的意思是有点像 那个..
You mean, sort of like them... what are they called?
姐妹团
Les Girls?
以前我总去看
Yeah, I've seen 'em in Sydney when I was young!
那些太棒了
Fantastic! Just terrific!
保博 你正看这的最出名的 姐妹团
Bob, you are looking at probably the most famous Les Girl ever produced!
你在开玩笑吗 饶了我把
You're kidding me! Give me a break.
我一直都没出名 我没开玩笑
I was never that famous. I'm not joking.
我是说 我不一定见过你 但...
What? I mean, I wouldn't have seen you, but...
那些是30年间的事了 你们会惊奇的
That was 30 years back. Oh, you'd be surprised.
我给你表演 我唱歌!
Me perform for you. Me sing...!
不 你不演出 他们演 不是你
No, Cynthia. You no perform. They perform, not you.
[Shouts viciously]
好真正的姐妹团表演
Well! A real live Les Girls show.
值得庆祝
Right, this calls for a celebration.
[Band plays old-time dance music]
也许这不是好主意 闭嘴
Maybe this isn't a good idea. Oh, shut your twat.
你记得我们裙下的轰动吗 你还记得吗
Our frocks were the sensation of Broken Hill, remember?
直到他们知道 什么叫裙子
Broken Hill had a K-Mart. They knew what a frock was.
天那 你看看 那些女人穿的是什么
Christ, you should see this woman's dress.
那不是裙子 是麻袋
It's not a frock. It's a piece of corrugated iron!
[Knocks at door]
我能进来吗 要是单身就行
Can I come in? Only if you're single!
哦 你看起来好极了
Oh, you look, uh... incredible.
我们哪找的那家伙
Where did we find him?
你嘴还挺甜
Keep dishing out the compliments, Bob.
到处都是这样的家伙
Flattery gets you everywhere.
你的可爱的 老婆呢?
Now, where's that lovely wife of yours?
她在家 她不准来酒吧
She's at home. She's, uh... not allowed in the pub anymore.
真的 为什么
Really? Why?
她酗酒 当她在酒吧的时候 她老是出丑
Alcohol problem - when she's in the pub she makes a fool of herself.
我知道她的感觉
I know how she feels.
我们都在等 你准备好了吗
Well, we're all waiting. Are you ready?
保搏
Bob...
还是取消演出吧
...we're having second thoughts.
你不能后退 所有人都来了
You can't back out. Every man and his dog's here.
他们没有锁在一起
They're not chained up are they? [Chuckles] Oh, you blokes!
对不起 孩子们
[Softly] Sorry. You girls.
你们会没事的 相信我
You'll be fine. Take my word for it.
[Curses viciously]
[MEN WHISTLE AND CHEER]
[MEN WHOOP AND SHOUT INSIDE PUB]
[Screams and curses with fury]
[Screams]
[BAND PLAYS COUNTRY MUSIC]
没有比这件事 让我更喜欢的了
SONG: There's nothing more that I'd like to do
和我一起跳舞
Than take the floor and dance with you
跳舞 我们一直跳舞
Keep dancing Let's keep dancing
扭呀!
Shake it! Shake it!
忸你的屁股 棒极了
Shake your groove thing Shake your groove thing, yeah, yeah!
展示他们呀 就是现在
Show them how to do it now Show them how to do it now!
好!
YEAH!
好极了
MAN: Yeah, right.
[Cynthia trills ecstatically]
她来了
MAN: Here she goes! [Men whistle and cheer]
[SLEAZY SAX OPHONE JAZZ]
[Men keep whistling and cheering]
[Men whoop and whistle]
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
她不会把
Oh, she's not!
她?
Is she?
你不能用 乒乓球那样...
Oh, you can't do that with a ping-pong ball!
[AII cheer enthusiastically]
你想打赌吗?
Do you want a bet?
[Men cheer and shout]
噢 噢 噢 噢
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
[Men cheer]
[Laughs hysterically]
[Keeps laughing]
[POP!] [Men cheer]
帮我
[Screams] Help me! [Men boo]
我不要离开 帮我
He's taking me away! Help me!
[Laughs hysterically] [Keeps screaming]
我走了
I'm going!
我们不能节约决吗
Darling, there's nothing we can't work out.
你不是好人. 你别傻了
You no good man. Now, don't be silly.
你要是要好老婆 你就要是个好老公
You want good wife - you be good husband.
别走
Darling, don't go.
我不喜欢你了 你的太小了
I no like you anyway. You got little ding-a-ling.
[KOOKABURRAS LAUGH]
有些日子你 跟们不该下床
Some days you just shouldn't get out of bed.
我的意见是 你不应该在这等
In my opinion, you should wait here
为了新的油箱
for the new gas tank from Coober Pedy.
听我的最后选择
Then again, you listened to my last opinion.
算了 我们走了
Forget it, Bob. It's time we made a move.
我只是个玩票的
I'm just a gifted amateur around here.
一条裙子
There's no way a nice frock and a catchy tune
怎么能比得上 3个乒乓球
can compete with three ping-pong balls, two cigarettes and beer.
我们这次不冒险 别在意 保博
I'll play it safe and stick to the main drag, pardon the pun.
再见
Well, goodbye, Bob.
谢谢你的一切
Thanks for a very educational stay.
能那样开瓶酒
I'd love to be able to open a bottle like that.
感谢你们的诚恳
Bernadette, it's certainly been an honour
很荣幸人是你们
meeting a member of Les Girls.
十分荣幸
And it's been an honour to meet a gentleman.
相信我现在绅士 不多了
Believe me, Bob, these days gentlemen are an endangered species.
不像人妖 却越来越多
Unlike bloody drag queens who just keep breeding like rabbits!
[Laughs heartily]
[Adam babbles loudly in mock Japanese]
噢 我靠
[ENGINE STALLS] Oh fuck it!
保博 我们能一起走吗
Bob! Fancy a free ride to Coober Pedy?
听着 有件事我们要直说
Now, listen, Bob. Let's get one thing straight.
我们穿裙子 不意味着你就要穿裤子
We wear the frocks, but that doesn't mean you wear the pants.
好 我睡哪里
Right. Where do I sleep?
那都可以
Oh! Anywhere that takes your fancy!
车顶就不错
[Laughs] The roof will do me fine.
谢谢你
Thank you, Bob.
我不知道要说什么
I don't know what to say.
没关系我宁愿 早些到达
That's alright. Might as well get there earlier. Bit of R and R.
我需要那些
God knows I need it.
[MAJESTIC OPERA MUSIC PLAYS]
我能不能问你个死人问题 你要是不介意的话
Can I ask you a personal question, if you don't mind?
问吧 什么
Sure. Why?
你为什么...?
Why do you... you know?
你是说那个6万4千元的问题吗
You mean the $64,000 question?
乖孩子 现在不要弄坏包装
WOMAN: That's the girl. Don't tear the wrapping paper.
剪断丝带 看看圣诞老人 送来了什么
Just slide the ribbon off and we can see what Santa's brought you.
看看呀
Here it comes now.
是什么
What is it?
是 是..
Oh, it's a... It's a...
一辆混凝土车
...cement mixer.
你又换了礼物
Have you been changing the cards around again, Ralph?
所以 我大概也 没什么选择
So, I guess I had no choice in the matter.
阿 你是怎么开的车 你这笨蛋
ADAM: For fuck's sake! Watch where you're driving, you stupid bitch!
你要杀了我吗
You trying to fucken kill me?
我错了
My fault!
对不起 我还以为是班尼
Sorry, Bob. I thought it was Bernadette.
[ENGINE SPLUTTERS AND CHOKES]
一二三 二二三 三二三
One-two-three, two-two-three, three-two-three...
你现在好多了
Now you're getting it.
谁教你的 我老婆
Who taught you to waltz? My wife.
噢好极了
Oh, how sweet.
你和老婆每星期2 去跳华尔兹
You and the missus down at Arthur Murray's every Tuesday
锻炼锻炼
practising your hearts out.
令我作呕
Makes me want to sick up.
结婚了
Married?
对
Yes, married.
我们也当当发现
We've only recently discovered
他也是左右为难
young Anthony here bats for both teams.
我不是 我们不要这么直接
I do not! Oh, so we're straight?
不 我们不
No. Oh, we're not?
我们开始疑惑了
We're a donut puncher after all?
不 那我们是什么
No. Then what are we?
我他妈也不知道
I don't fucking know! [Laughs]
是他妈什么
What the fuck's that?
晚安
Good evening.
不错的晚上
Nice night for it.
好 晚安大家
Oh, OK. Goodnight then.
多么粗鲁的女人
What a rude woman.
[DESERT WIND BLOWS]
那是动力 那是散热风扇
And that's the power steering pump. And that's the radiator fan.
有趣 很简单
How interesting. Simple.
这就差不多是 所有的事情了
That's the rubber band that drives the whole thing...
噢 好
Oh! Yes!
谁想第一个洗澡
Hey! Who wants first bath?
呜~~
[Hoots] Whoo-ooh!
[GENTLE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC]
我赢了
I won!
[BIRDS CHATTER]
我能帮你吗
Can I help you, ma'am?
[BIRDS SCREECH]
[AII keep whooping and laughing]
关上他
OK! Turn her over!
[ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE BACKFIRES]
['I DON'T CARE IF THE SUN DON'T SHINE' PLAYS]
我不在乎太阳 是否发光
[Mimes to singing] I don't care if the sun don't shine
我们在晚上娱乐
I get my loving in the evening time
我和我的宝贝儿
When I'm with my baby
和太阳没关系
It's no fun with the sun around
因为我们在落山后 出发
But I get going when the sun goes down
我和我的宝贝儿
And I meet my baby
我们亲吻 亲呀亲
That's when we kiss and kiss and kiss
我们继续
And then we kiss some more
不要问我们亲吻的次数
Don't ask how many times we kiss
没有人记得
At a time like this who keeps score?
我不在乎太阳 是否发光
So, I don't care if the sun don't shine
我们在晚上娱乐
I get my loving in the evening time
我和我的宝贝儿
When I'm with my baby!
[BRASS SECTION PLAYS INTERLUDE]
就是那里
BOB: That's it over there.
房子还可以 有淋浴
It's an OK room - with a shower. Bags first!
是热水吗?
Is hot water all you think about?
还有好吃的
No. A shower, bed and nice meal will do fine.
如果你认为还会有电视 那你就错了
If you think I'm just going to watch television, you're wrong.
这里不安全
Now, look. You blokes watch your back.
这是一个不怎么的镇子
It's a pretty tough town.
他们挖坑 在埋上
They go down holes, blow things up, then come up again.
这就是他们的一生
That sums things up. Oh, fabulous!
欢迎加入我们 如果你没事做
You're welcome to hang out with us, Bob.
去找朋友 喝几杯
I'm meeting some of the boys in the old drive-in for a booze-up.
像以前一样
Like the old days.
我想去男士俱乐部
I want to go to the boys club!
你会很快乐或者是 在房间里看电视
You'll have supper with us or stay in your room and watch TV.
[TELEVISION PLAYS]
阿!
Ha!
他是好人 我们的保博
He's a good man, our Bob.
对
Yeah.
但不是我要的类型
Not my type, though.
别和我来这套
Oh! Don't come the raw prawn with me!
我早就看出来了 你起了色心
I can spot the fluttering of a beaded lash from 300 paces!
别逗了他太老了
Oh, get out! He's far too old.
我也是一样 恩
Mind you, so am I. Mmm.
你那个新娘呢
Did you catch that mail-order bride?
我要问问 他为什么要结婚
Why'd he marry? I'm dying to ask.
对不起 没关系
Oops! Sorry. It's alright.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我们是最好的老公
You're the world's best husband.
如果有机会 还会是好爸爸
And, given the chance, a perfectly good father too.
你真的这么认为吗
Do you really think so?
你为什么要先小孩的事
Why? Thinking about children?
有什么关系吗
Yes, as a matter of fact.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
你有没有 德州牌眼膏吗
Um, do you have 'The Texas Chainsaw Mascara'?
想过要孩子吗
You ever wanted kids?
是的 可是我学着 不去想他们
Sure. But I've learned not to think about it.
你认为我这个人妖 能养孩子吗
You think an old queen's capable of raising a child?
伊丽莎白 做得不错呀
Well, Elizabeth did a pretty good job.
查里斯是个好孩子
Prince Charles is a wonderful boy.
但埃德华却令人担心
Edward's still a bit of a worry.
怎么了 如果他们都像亚当怎么办
What happens if they turn out like Adam?
那你就把他们 退回去
You stuff them back in and ask for a refund.
傻瓜
Stupid little shit.
我不敢想像他搞得是什么鬼
I dread to think what he's up to.
[CROWD OF MEN LAUGH AND TALK DRUNKENLY]
哦
Oooh.
你好
Hello.
我是新来的
I'm new in town.
没开玩笑
No kidding.
我可以来点喝的吗
Could I have a bloody Mary, please?
我们这只有啤酒.
It's a beer or nothing... sweetheart.
拿我就要啤酒吧
Well, I'd better have a beer then.
干杯
Cheers.
[MURMURING AND SNIGGERING]
你们都看什么
What are you all looking at?
对不起
I'm sorry.
不是有意的 我们这里不是常有女人
Didn't mean to stare. We don't usually get women down here.
哦
Oh.
那么 一般女人能在这干什么 除了看电视
So what do women do around here besides watching videos?
哈哈哈 看看这是谁来了
Well, well, well! Look who we have here.
你认识他吗
You know that bloke, do you?
不
No.
谁能带我四下看看
So... who's going to show me the sights?
我很乐意
It'd be my pleasure.
哦
Oh.
这个怎么样
So, how about it?
你这个超级 混蛋
I suppose a fuck's now out of the question.
兄弟们 抓住她
[Others shout] Get her, Frank! Go, Frank!
来呀谁想看看我的秘密基地
Come on, boys! Who wants to see my map of Tasmania?
我从来都没告诉我的父母 我的童年是怎么样的
I never got to tell my parents what a wonderful childhood I'd had.
后来我掩了后 他们就 再也没和我说过话
They never spoke to me again after I'd had... the chop.
我想我有些事 要和你说
I think I have something to tell you.
哦 妈的
[Adam laughs breathlessly] Oh, shit.
抓住她
MAN: Get after her!
[DRAMATIC MUSIC BUILDS]
[Adam laughs hysterically]
好了 别忘了你们的绅士风度
OK, fellas! Don't forget how to treat a lady.
你他妈的怪物
You fucking freak!
[Groans]
把她放倒
Hold him down.
劈开她的双腿
Spread his legs apart.
哦请不要
Oh, no. Please, don't!
伙计们 停下来
Frank, stop!
你们她妈的再做什么 快他妈的停下
Stop! What the fuck do you think you're doing?!
你认识这个 贱货
You mean you do know this cocksucker.
放开他
Get off him, you mongrel!
他是在开玩笑的 你们离她远点
He was joking, OK? You leave the little bugger alone.
一开他
Get out of there, Bob.
冷静点
Calm down, Frank.
把她放下 要不然 下一个就是你
Put the faggot down and get out or you'll be next.
伙计们 快滚开
Frank! Get out of there!
不要在那里逞英雄了
Stop flexing your muscles you big pile of budgie turd.
如果你要是真的想
Your mates will be more impressed
那就滚会酒吧 去操两头猪吧
if you go back to the pub and fuck a few pigs on the bar.
班尼...
Bernadette, please...
班尼
Bernadette?!
好呀 看看这镇 都来了些什么人
Well, I'll be darned. The whole circus is in town.
我想你也想操吧 对吗
I suppose you want a fuck too, do you?
来 班尼 来干我
Come on, Bernadette. Come and fuck me.
好吧
That's it.
快过来干我
Come on. Come and fuck me.
来
Come on. [MUSIC BUILDS TO A CRESCENDO]
干我
Fuck me.
[Groans]
看呀 你现在惨了
There, now you're fucked.
你这他妈的傻逼 天那
TONY: You stupid bloody idiot! Drugs, for Christ's sake!
我希望你 现在高兴点了
Well, three cheers for you! I hope you're happy now!
[DOOR SLAMS VIOLENTLY]
你这个臭婊子
You bloody fuckwit!
[Keeps sobbing]
太好玩了
It's funny.
我们在一起
We all sit around
抄起架来 都骂得那么难听
mindlessly slagging off that vile stink-hole of a city.
但我们互相照顾
But in its own strange way it takes care of us.
我不知道 那个恶心的墙...
I don't know if that ugly wall of suburbia's been put there
来阻止他们 骚扰我们
to stop them getting in or us getting out.
来
Come on.
别让他领你沮丧
Don't let it drag you down.
让他过去把
Let it toughen you up.
我能打是因为 我学过
I can only fight because I've learnt to.
做一天男人 第二天的女人就容易了
Being a man one day and a woman the next isn't easy.
对不起我帮不了你 不要担心
Sorry. Can't help you. No worries, Pete.
我们怎么去 我们的目的地
Are we bunny-hopping all the way to Alice?
他说我们的救星 离这里很远
The man to help's a fair way out of town.
多远
Like how fair?
几百公里
Couple of hundred klicks fair.
没关系 我们今天又没什么事
No matter. I've go nothing else to do today. Let's get out of here.
我们走
Come on, Adam. We're not here.
['A FINE ROMANCE' PLAYS]
不要亲吻
SONG: A fine romance with no kisses
我的朋友 就到这了
A fine romance, my friend, this is
我们像 热土豆
We should be like a couple of hot tomatoes...
我发火时说 错了话
Some things are said in the heat of the moment.
对不起 我昨晚对你 很生气
I'm sorry I got angry with you last night.
其实你是罪有应得
Oh, I dare say you deserved it.
不管怎么样 不提了
Anyway, that's enough of that.
跟你一起有了新的 经历
This is quite an experience sitting with you now.
我敢大胆的说
I can quite safely say
你的衣着品味 真是太糟糕了
that I think your taste in clothing is absolutely terrible
因为你没什么可说的 对吗
because you can't say a word, can you?
噢 这太好笑了
Oh, this is great fun!
[ENGINE BACKFIRES LOUDLY] [Whistles]
我们不用找那个 有油箱的救星了
We're going to have a problem finding this guy with the tank.
为什么这么说 因为他不存在
Why say that? Because he's not out here.
他不在这 他在埃里斯
He's out here. He's in Alice.
我有段时间会不去了
I can't go back to Coober Pedy for a while.
我不是最不受欢迎的人
I'm not the most popular bloke back there anymore.
[Gasps]
哦
Ooof!
[ORIENTAL MUSIC PLAYS]
你好
Hello.
Hello!
你是谁 我是你老婆
Who are you? I your wife!
我要回家了 你不能回去
Guess I'll be going home then. You no going!
我也去 我是你老婆
I coming too. I your wife!
你老婆
See? I your wife!
傻女还
Silly girl.
没好好做家务
Should've done her homework better.
她一直以为 我是雪梨来的
[Laughs] She always thought... She thought I was from Sydney.
你为什么把她带回家
Why did you bring her home?
她是我老婆
She was me wife.
你买不出去吗
ADAM: Couldn't you sell her off?
噢 派对完了
Oh, the party's over, everyone. It talks.
管不住一个三八
Can't keep a good bitch down.
几点了 我们能到埃里斯吗
What time will we be in Alice Springs?
令天晚一些
Late tomorrow arvo.
你们要呆多久
How long will you be staying?
不知道
Don't know.
要住几天
A couple of days maybe.
明天是我的大日子 我们要拜见尊夫人
A big day for you tomorrow! We'll all meet the missus!
我看见你笑了
I saw that smile, Felicia!
你在说一个字
One derogatory word
我就把你带回去
and I'll take you back to your mate in Coober Pedy.
来吧大家伙们 明天可不好过呀
Please, everyone. Tomorrow will be tough.
我们就别火上浇油了
Please don't make it any harder.
我们在说笑 没有你的批准 我们现在不敢说话了
We're only teasing. We won't open our mouths until you give the word.
然后就能开口了
And then it's open season.
[MOSQUITO BUZZES]
好了 睡觉吧
Oh, well. Time for bed.
我要找个好老婆
Got to look good for the wife.
来亚当 自己去睡觉
Come along, Adam. Time for your beauty sleep.
来吧
[Groans] Come on!
你们两个尽兴
Will you two be joining us?
我要在喝一杯
I just thought I'd have one for the road.
你呢 保博
How about you, Bob?
好主意
Sounds good to me.
那好 明天见
Alright, then. See you in the morning.
晚安
Goodnight!
在来一个蛋糕吗
Another piece of cake, Bob?
不 哦
Ah, no. Oh.
和我说说你
So... tell me about you.
不能抱怨
Can't complain. [Snickers]
生活简单了
Life's a lot simpler now.
30年来 在这世界上
Spent 30 years wandering around the world
最后才发现才是起点最好
only to find I was better off where I started.
起码是自己的地方
Not much, but it's my turf.
哦妈的
Oooh! Shit!
亚当
Adam!
阿!
怎么了 猜猜昨天谁没回家
What? Guess who didn't come home?
我等了一生了
I've waited all my life for this.
半你把她的蛋糕放在 了雨中
Bernice has left her cake out in the rain!
[BIows a raspberry] [Laughs]
有个遗憾
[Sings] Hava nagila Have a hangover
有个遗憾 咳咳
Hava nagila Hi hi hi!
[BACKGROUND MUSICAL ACCOMPANIMENT]
嘀嘀嘀
Di di, di-di-di-di Di di, di-di-di-di
[FULL CHOIR AND ORCHESTRA JOIN IN]
有个遗憾
Hava nagila Hava nagila
Hava nagila V'nish m'cha, hey!
有个遗憾
Hava nagila Hava nagila
Hava nagila V'nish m'cha
嘿
Aaaahhhhhh, aaaahhhhhh, aaaahhhhhh HEY!
我的后背疼死了
My fucking back's killing me.
我要大便
I need a crap.
你要我去吗
Do you want me to go in? I'll go.
对不起 你们不能打着停这
MAN: Excuse me. You can't park your bus here.
你们要住在这吗 对不起
Are you planning on staying here? I'm sorry...
我想找巴伯
Could you direct me to Marian Barber?
我们是雪梨来的歌唱团
We're the cabaret act from Sydney.
哦 对对 进去吧
Oh, right, right! Just go through to reception.
谢谢 别客气
Thanks. No worries.
看呀 人妖们来了
It's alright, Lenny. It's the drag queens!
来呀 保博 试试你的新裙子
Come on, Bob. Let's go try on your new frock.
阿
G'day.
就在酒吧后面
Just over there by the bar.
谢谢
Thanks.
不 那3歌笨蛋还没到呢
WOMAN: No, those three kegs didn't arrive.
我今天就要 不是明天 是今天
I need them today - not tomorrow, but today.
你这笨蛋
You're a doll.
混蛋
What an arsehole.
[Screams]
天那 老公
Oh, my God! Husband! Husband!
看到你太好了 老婆
It's so good to see you! Hiya, wife!
你来晚了 其他的人在哪
You're late. Where are the others? Oh, they're outside.
你瘦了 你这个老同性恋
You've lost weight, you old queer. About fucken time!
我都能钻到你以前的游泳衣里了
I can fit into your old one-piece - the one with the sunflowers.
你要干什么
What do you do with it?
做戏服 你知道的
'The Poseidon Adventure' routine. You know, Shelley Winters.
[Both laugh happily]
他在哪
Where is he?
我要打你一顿
WOMAN: I'd like to give you a good spanking.
你能行的
You can get it!
拍拍拍
Spank, spank, spank!
我要把你放在我的膝盖上
I'll put you over my knee.
我要打你的屁屁
I'll spank, spank you back! Oops!
宝
Benj.
记得阿提吗
Do you remember Tick?
你好阿提
Hello, Tick.
你好
Hello.
[TALKING IN BACKGROUND]
该死的酒吧在那
Where's the bloody bar?
[AII talk over one another]
贝先生
Mr Belrose?
什么事
Yes?
祝贺 是个男孩
Congratulations. It's a boy.
[BAB Y WAILS]
哦
Oh!
妈的 你还好吗
MARIAN: Shit! Are you OK?
怎么了 天那 帮忙
What's the matter? Oh, my God! Help.
天那 为什么你不和我们说
Christ's sake, Mitz, why didn't you tell us?
为什么拿我们当傻子
Why did you shock me like that?
哦
Ooh!
我头上的包越来越大
This lump on my head's growing by the second.
我快要演出了
I'm making my Northern Territory debut
我却像被打的卡通人物
looking like a fucking Warner Bros cartoon character
用铁东西打的
has hit me with an iron.
我说你想巫婆 闭嘴
You look more like a Disney witch. Shut up!
我才不像
At least I don't look like
有人要打你得脸
somebody's tried to open a can of beans with my face.
对不起我不期望你们烦我 两个星期
Sorry. I didn't want you bagging me for two weeks.
现在有什么不同吗
What difference does it make now?
大约离我头两尺
About two inches to my head.
看到他了吗 他拿了我的香水
See him? He's got my profile.
我会恶心
I'm gonna be sick.
他知不知道 你是谁
Let's be practical - does he know who you are?
他知道你是干什么的吗
Does he know what you do?
他知道他的爸爸 是从事娱乐业的
He knows his father's in the show business cosmetics industry.
天那 我不明白
[Scoffs] Oh, Lord! I don't understand.
那就别明白了
You don't, so stop trying to.
那才好 比明白好
It'll be fine! It'd better be.
你好 你都快把镜子照烂了
Hello! Oh, stop wearing out that mirror!
你怎么不敲门
Do you always knock? Always.
你有什么怕看的吗 有吗
Haven't got anything to hide, have you?
好吧 姐妹们 还有10分钟
Alright, girls, you're on in 10 minutes.
你出娘胎便是出场了
You've been on since birth.
外边有很多观众
The word's out. There's a big crowd.
有多少 客满了
How big? A full house.
宝在哪 没事 他在睡觉
Where's Benj? Safe and sound, asleep in bed.
什么事都不用担心 我的小帅哥
Don't worry about a thing, my little powder puff.
我能进来吗
[KNOCKING] BOB: Can I come in?
看 那才叫绅士
Now, there's a gentleman.
当然可以
Of course you can, Bob.
我姑妈在这吗
My Aunt Minnie in here?
祝你们走运
Just... wanted to wish you luck.
谢谢你 保博 谢谢
Thank you, Bob. Thanks.
希望可以弥补上次的
To make up for last time.
谢谢 太美了
Thank you. That's so thoughtful.
大家准备好
Let's get this show on the road. You, out.
10分钟 祝好运
10-minute curtain call. Good luck.
你老婆真厉害
That's quite a wife you've got, Mitz.
她有什么爱好吗 用舌头擦坦克?
What's her hobby - sanding back oil tanker hulls with her tongue?
他确实厉害
She sure is something!
哦 孩子们
Oh! Chookers, girls.
小心 我的脑袋
Watch my jaw! Mind my head.
我们耀眼吗
Aren't we faaa-bulous!
先生们女士们 列斯达赌场为你献上
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen, Lasseters Casino, Alice Springs
阿提姐妹小组
presents Miss Mitzi del Gra,
米芝 菲利西和班尼小姐
Miss Felicia Jolly Good Fellow and Miss Bernadette Basinger -
沙漠中的姐妹
the Sisters of the Simpson Desert.
[DISCO MUSIC PLAYS]
遇见瑞特先生
[Mimes to singing] Meeting Mr Right
我梦想中的男人
The man of my dreams
他给了我真爱
The one who showed me true love or at least it seemed
他的棕色皮肤 黑色眼睛
With brown cocoa skin and curly black hair
他看着我的眼神
Just the way he looks at me - that gentle, loving stare
最后你还是自己来了
Finally you came along
我的感觉不会错
The way I feel about you it just can't be wrong
如果你知道 我是怎么感觉你的
If you only knew the way I feel about you
我无法描述
I just can't describe it
不不不
Oh, no, no
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的嘴唇之间
Right in front of my face My two lips can't describe it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我们只能面对
Right in front of my face and I just cannot hide it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的嘴唇之间 我不能形容
Right in front of my face My two lips can't describe it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我们只能面对
Right in front of my face and I just cannot hide it...
看起来有好几次
Seemed so many times he seemed to be the one
但总要有一些小乐趣
But all he ever wanted was to have a little fun
现在你独自来到我的世界
But now you've come along and brightened up my world
我的心能感到 我是个很特别的女孩
In my heart I feel it I'm that special kind of girl
最后你还是来了
Finally you came along
我的感觉不会错
The way I feel about you it just can't be wrong
如果你知道 我是怎么感觉你的
If you only knew the way I feel about you
我无法描述
I just can't describe it
不不不
Oh, no, no
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我无法形容
Right in front of my face My two lips can't describe it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我们只能面对
Right in front of my face and I just cannot hide it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我无法形容
Right in front of my face My two lips can't describe it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我们只能面对
Right in front of my face and I just cannot hide it...
最后
Finally
哇
WWhoa
最后 耶
Finally Yeah, yeah
哇~~
Whoa-oh-oh
最好 宝贝儿
Finally, baby
耶
Y ea h, yea h, ow
宝贝儿
Baby, yeah, yeah
耶
Y ea h, yea h, ow
Baby, yeah, yeah
耶
Y ea h, yea h, ow
Baby, yeah, yeah
耶
Y ea h, yea h, ow
Baby, yeah, yeah
耶
Y ea h, yea h, ow
[DISCO MUSIC CONTINUES]
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我无法形容
Right in front of my face My two lips can't describe it
最后它还是发生了
Finally it's happened to me
在我们的面前 我们只能面对
Right in front of my face and I just cannot hide it
最后 哦耶
Finally Oh, yeah
耶
Yeah, yeah...
最后 耶~
Finally Oh, yeah.
[SPARSE APPLAUSE]
再来一个 好
MARIAN: More! BOB: Bravo!
漂亮 大家伙们
Beauty! Come on, everybody!
再来一个
Yay! More!
Yes! More! [Benji cheers loudly]
嘿嘿
Hey-hey! More! More!
[AII three keep cheering and clapping]
你们太妙了
More! You were wonderful!
我们要你在唱一首
We want more! Yes!
再来一个
Magnificent! Yay!
Bravo! Whoo! More!
再来一个
We want more! [CROWD GASPS AND EX CLAIMS]
醒醒
Come on, snap out of it.
快点
Come on, mate. [Groans]
你没事的
You'll be fine.
亲爱的
Come on, love.
哦 这就对了
Oh. That's it, mate.
吓死我们了
Scared us all for a minute.
他就是会抢镜头
Had to have extra attention, didn't you?
不错
Nice one, lovey, nice one.
妈的
Shit!
你在干什么
What are you doing, Marian?
你这个骗子 你和我说他在睡觉
You liar! You said he was in bed.
和你的酒吧
Shh! Drink your daiquiri.
我不喜欢喝这个
I hate bloody daiquiri!
你不喜欢 你喜欢的
You don't. You love bloody daiquiris.
我现在知道人妖 为什么爱用大杯子了
Now I know why drag queens drink from big glasses.
让他们的手 看起来小一点
To make their hands look smaller! Oh, ha ha, Marian!
你怎么和孩子说的 我真是太尴尬了
What do I tell the boy? I've never been so embarrassed.
你太敏感了 真的?
You're overreacting. Really?!
你只是个演戏的
Yes. You're being a drama queen.
要是不演了 还会是个好爸爸
You'd better drop that shit if you're gonna be a good father.
我做了我该做的 先在该你了
And don't pretend to be surprised. It's your turn.
不是永远 哪怕是几个月
Not forever - maybe just a couple of months.
为什么是现在
Yeah, but why now?
因为我8年没放过假了
Because I haven't had a holiday in eight years.
我要歇一歇 我要休息
I need a rest, Tick. I need space.
我以前也这么说过
Reminds me of something I said. Well, I do.
还有也是时候让他认他爸爸了
It's time he knew his father anyway.
这就是问题了
Yeah, that's the problem.
我怎么和他说
What do I tell him?
你想我说什么 撒谎
What do you assume I do - lie?
把所有的事都弄糟了
Assumption's the mother of all fuck-ups.
别烦我 和他说去
Bitch to him, not me.
谢谢你的建议
You might be surprised. Thanks for the free advice.
[FAINT TALKING AND LAUGHING]
是谁
BERNADETTE: Who is it?
是我 保博
It's me, Bob.
你的花快屑了
Your flowers were being mangled.
我帮你救了他们
Thought I'd rescue them for you.
好主意 谢谢
Good idea. Thanks.
[Makes shooting sounds]
怎么了
What's the matter?
没事
Nothing.
[TV PLAYS IN BACKGROUND]
你知道你爸爸 是干什么的吗
Know what your father does for a living?
知道
Yeah.
[Keeps making shooting sounds]
那你也知道他不 很喜欢女孩子
So you know he doesn't really like girls then?
那他有男朋友吗
Does he have a boyfriend at the moment?
没有
No.
妈妈也没有
Neither does Mum.
她有个女朋友 但分手了
She had a girlfriend, but she got over her.
想来我房间里玩吗 我有积木
Want to play in my room? I've got Lego.
当然
Sure.
快点我们要走了
Come on, Butch. Get moving.
我们自己都 不能收场了
We can't brand the cattle by ourselves.
昨晚的演出不错 结尾总是那样
Great show last night. You always end a number like that?
从来都是
[Bob woIf whistIes ] Always. [Bob wolf whistles]
你想每晚接她下班吗
How'd you like to pick her up every night, Sundance?
很乐意
Be a pleasure.
也包括勾引女人 上床
That might include tucking the lady into bed, Jeff.
能拿多少钱
What's the pay like, Marian?
他终有一天会惹上麻烦
He'll get himself into trouble one day.
只要用心 便会交上好运
And you might just be the lucky fellow.
来 大家上车
BOB: All aboard!
写一封信
SONG: So take a letter, Maria
给我老婆
Address it to my wife...
别总是含沙射影
Watch it with the innuendos.
给我来个痛快的
Give me a clear shot at this.
你说什么叫 痛快的
You call dressing like a Xanadu production number a clear shot?
摆脱 阿提 谁在和谁开玩笑
Come on, Tick! Who's kidding who?
他很确定
He sure as shit isn't.
给我律师一份
Sehd a ocopy to hmy awyer
要开始新的生活
Gotta start a new life
你遇到过很多事情
You've been many things
但是大多 对我有益
But most of all a good secretary to me...
恩
MARIAN: Um, wave...
我在做什么 游泳
ADAM: What am I doing? Swimming!
恩
Um...
玛丽
Murray.
石头 玛丽克斯
Rock... Murray rock...
克斯汉森
River rock... Oh, Rock! Rock Hudson!
笨蛋 你真的苯
Silly dag! Didn't you get Doris Day?
该我了该我了 好 你来
My turn! My turn! OK, smartypants, you try.
那来吧
Come on, then.
是... 人
It's a... Person.
女人 猫
A sexy woman. BOB: Cat?
有名的女人
Famous woman.
恩 阿...
Um... Oh, ah...
婴儿 牛
Baby. Oh, ah, rocking.
我知道
Oh, I know this one.
马 恶猫
Racehorse! Cat. Scary cat.
老鼠
Er, scary moose.
狗
Scary dog?
我知道 不
I know, I know! No?
噢 是林提
BERNADETTE: Oh, Lindy Chamberlain.
[AII laugh]
乖孩子
That was appalling, Benji.
是谁教你的 妈妈教的
Who taught you that? Mum did.
说谎 我也这么想
Lies! All lies! I thought so.
来呀 亚当
[Chuckles] Come on, Adam.
起来
[Groans] Up!
我们没时间了
Time is against us.
我们有事情要做
And we have things to do.
来吧
Come on, you butch thing, you.
不 我不去
No, no, count me out.
都在等你 来 阿提
All for one... ADAM: Come on, Tick.
不
No.
恩
Hmm.
来我们换衣服去
Come on, Adam. Let's get frocked.
[BIRDS TWITTER]
那么...
So, uh...
终于有老爸了 感觉怎么样
...er, what's it like to finally have a father?
还行
It's OK.
昨天对不起
I'm sorry about last night.
我不是老穿女人的衣服的
I don't always dress up in women's clothes.
我是说 你不要误解
I mean, you know, don't get the wrong idea.
恩
Um...
我也不容易
I do a lot of different stuff.
你知道 就像...
You know, like... EIvis and Gary Glitter.
神父?
abba Abba?
我不应该知道 那些东西
I'm not supposed to know about the Abba show.
但是我想看看
But I'd really like to see it.
你能给我演吗
Would you do Abba for me?
当然
Sure.
你知道我是什么 对吗?
You know what I am, don't you?
妈妈说你最聪明
Mum says you're the best in the business.
哈 你妈妈 老是爱吹牛
Ah, well, your mother was always prone to exaggeration.
你回到家 会找个男朋友吗
Will you have a boyfriend when we're in Sydney?
可能
Maybe.
那很好
That's good.
[HEAVENLY SINGING]
来呀 我们去哪
Come on! Where are we going?
去了解那些最好的事情
To unleash the best in the business.
我有个梦想
I had a dream.
[HEAVENLY SINGING CONTINUES]
[MUSIC SWELLS TRIUMPHANTLY]
[MUSIC BUILDS TO TRIUMPHANT CLIMAX]
哇~
[Breathlessly] Well...
我们做到了
...we did it.
那没有尽头
It never ends, does it?
是那么广阔
All that space.
现在呢
So, what now?
我要回家
I think I want to go home.
我也是
Me too.
那好吧
Well, then...
我们演出完 就回家
...let's finish the shows and go home.
[MAJESTIC MUSIC PLAYS]
再没给我你电话之前 你不能走
Don't go without leaving me your number.
没问题
Already taken care of, Jeff.
就现在酒吧 的厕所里
It's at the bar end of the men's cubicle -
要玩 找菲利沙
For a good time, phone Felicia.
我们能去麦当劳吗 当然
Can we stop at McDonald's? Good idea.
我已经吃够了那些 该死的食物
I've had enough of this shitty food. Fucking crayfish.
你是怎么开始的
Where the hell do you start?
老公 你坦白点
Lay it on the line, husband.
不要隐瞒 这是关键
Don't conceal anything - that's the key.
如果他不喜欢 他可以卖票回来
If he doesn't like it, stiff bickies, he can always come back.
人家要是 议论我怎么办
What happens when people hear about Mitzi's minor?
是你的问题 不是他的
That's your problem, not his.
你有选择 他长大了 也会有他自己的
Morals are a choice. He'll decide his own when he's ready.
那好吧 我们准备好了
Well, that's it. You're all packed.
你开玩笑 还有班尼的鞋呢
You're joking?! Bernadette's shoes aren't on board yet.
我讨厌说这个 我希望我们可以一起走
Hate to say this - wish I was going with you.
你的油箱没事了
Your gas tank will be fine.
油门就是另一码事了
Your axle... may be another matter.
没事 路上有很多修车的
The road will be filled with bored mechanics
希望你们会慢慢 红起来
hoping some drag queens will spirit them away.
我们会的
We won't spirit gum at this rate.
班尼在哪 这
Where the hell's Bernadette? Here.
来呀 你的行李呢
Come on, cabanossi tits. Where are your bags?
在我的房间里
In my room.
我不想走 我要在这住一会
I'm not going. I'm staying here for a while.
真的吗?你怎么现在 才和我说这些
Oh, really? And you're choosing to tell us about this now?
她很早就和我说了
She told me a few weeks back.
我也需要帮手
Somebody's got to handle the guest entertainment while I'm away.
我明白了 看看谁在隐瞒什么
I get it. Who's been playing hide the sausage?
我们走吧 免得我吐了
Let's go before I throw up.
来 阿宝
Come on, Benj.
你能开着吗
Hope you can drive.
不拥抱 你就别想走
Hey, not without a hug!
哇 哇
Waaaa! Waaaa!
你确定吗
Are you sure?
不 我不确定
No, I'm not sure.
我永远不知道 除非你尝试一下
I'll never know unless I give it a shot.
我很嫉妒你
I'm as jealous as all hell.
妈的 我想哭了
Shit! Raccoon time again.
别忘了写信 再见
Don't forget to write! ADAM: See ya!
希望我能留下
Wish I was staying.
再见 你们保重
'Bye! 'Bye! Take care of her now!
再见
'Bye, Mum. 'Bye, Ralph!
Yeah, see ya, Ralph!
[Adam laughs]
我曾经骗过你
SONG: I've been cheated by you since I don't know when
现在该结束了
So I've made up my mind it must come to an end
看看现在的我
Look at me now Will I ever learn?
我不知道是怎么了
I don't know how
但是我突然失控了
But I suddenly lose control
我的心里有团火
There's a fire within my soul
你看一眼就能明白
Just one look and I can hear a bell ring
在看一眼你将永远不能忘怀
One more look and I forget everything
哇
WWhoa
我要再来一次
Mama mia Here I go again
我怎么能救你呢
My, my, how can I resist you? [AUDIENCE CHEERS AND CLAPS]
在展示一遍
Mama mia Does it show again
我现在很想念你
My, my, just how much I missed you?
我现在心碎了
Yes, I've been broken-hearted
从开始的那天
Blue since the day we parted
我什么我要让你走
Why, why did I ever let you go?
我也不知道
Mama mia Now I really know
我不应该让你走
My, my, I could never let you go...
[CHEERING AND WHISTLING]
我又伤心又生气
I've been angry and sad about things that you do
我不知道告诉你多少遍
I can't count all the times that I told you we're through
你怎么能这么做
How can you go when you slam the door?
我想你知道我的孤独
I think you know that you won't be away too long
你知道我的脆弱
You know that I'm not that strong
你看一眼就能明白
Just one look and I can hear a bell ring
在看一眼 你将难以忘怀
One more look and I forget everything
啊
WWhoa
我再一次的
Mama mia Here I go again
我怎么才能救你
My, my, how can I resist you?
展示一遍
[Audience joins in] Mama mia Does it show again
我现在想你
My, my, just how much I missed you?
我现在心碎
[CHEERING] Yes, I've been broken-hearted
从我们开始的时候
Blue since the day we parted
我怎么会让你走
Why, why did I ever let you go?
我真的不知道
Mama mia Now I really know
我不应该让你走
Why, why I could never let you go.
[CHEERING AND WHISTLING]
好了
No, that's enough.
哦我的奶子掉下来了
Oh, my tits are falling down!
[BALLOONS EXPLODE]
天那
Oh, Jesus!
谢谢
Thank you!
回到家真好
Thank you. It's good to be home!
[WILD CHEERING]
有时六月会下雪
SONG: Sometimes the snow comes down in June
有时太阳和月亮同在
Sometimes the sun goes round the moon
不看到你眼中的渴望
I see the passion in your eyes
有时是个惊喜
Sometimes it's all a big surprise
因为那是愿望的实现
'Cause there was a time when all I did was wish
你告诉我那是爱
You'd tell me this was love
那不是我希望的
It's not the way I hoped or how I planned
够了
But somehow it's enough
现在我们面对面
And now we're standing face to face
世界变得疯狂了吗
Isn't this world a crazy place?
那是因为我们的改变
Just when I thought our chance had passed
你留下了最好的
You go and save the best for last
你每晚都来见我
All of the nights you came to me
当那些苯女孩...
When some silly girl had set you free
你想知道是怎么发生的
You wondered how you'd make it through
我想知道你是怎么了
I wondered what was wrong with you
以为你变了心
'Cause how could you give your love to someone else
你不在和我分享你的梦
And share your dreams with me?
你再找着什么
Sometimes the very thing you're looking for
这是唯一的事情你看不见
Is the one thing you can't see
但现在我们面对面
But now we're standing face to face
世界疯狂了吗
Isn't this world a crazy place?
我想是因为我们变了
Just when I thought our chance had passed
你留下了最好的
You go and save the best for last
有时六月会下雪
Sometimes the snow comes down in June
有时太阳和月亮同在
Sometimes the sun goes round the moon
我想是因为我们变了
Just when I thought our chance had passed
你留下了最好的
You go and save the best for last
你留下了最好的..
You went and saved the best...
最后一次
...for last
耶 耶
Yeah, yeah.
[ORIENTAL MUSIC PLAYS]